Frank Farrell map collection
Geography and Map Division Library of Congress
Frank Farrell map collection. 1930-1965
G7821.S7 coll Farrell
21 maps: some colored; various sizes
1 folder
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Frank Farrell served in the Marine Corps as an interrogator and prosecutor for the International Military Tribunal for the Far East, Shanghai, China. His collection includes a map from World War II that depicts the military situation in China, maps of Guangxi Province, and various tourist maps. Some maps have annotations on the reverse in English and French and other maps are in Chinese.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Farrell, Frank, 1912-1983, collector.
Subjects
Military intelligence--China--maps.; World War, 1939-1945--China--Maps.
Places
Guangxi--maps.
Form/Genre
Military maps
Provenance
The materials were originally part of the Frank Farrell papers and transferred from the Manuscript Division.
Access and Restrictions
The Frank Farrell map collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Geography and Map Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes a map from World War II that depicts the military situation in China, maps of Guangxi Province, and various tourist maps. Some maps have annotations on the reverse in English and French and other maps are in Chinese.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into three series
Series I World War II intelligence maps of China
Series II Maps of Chinese provinces and cities
Series III Various tourist maps
Container List
- World War II intelligence maps of China
  - Map of China's war resistance in the rear of the enemy, 1945 (Item 1)
    XX Bombing Command E8E Section.
    Stamped "secret".
    Shows areas of communist guerilla activity.
  - Strategic Situation Map of China - Sheet 3, 1945 (Item 2)
    Office of Strategic Services ("OSS").
    Shows communist, nationalist, and Japanese forces.
    Shows military airfields.
  - Strategic Situation Map of China - Sheet 4, 1945 (Item 3)
    OSS.
    Stamped "secret control".
  - Greater China No. 3448-R & A, 1944 (Item 4)
    Provisional edition.
    Inset map: "Comparison of Greater China with the United States.
  - Situation -- Shantung April 1945 (Item 5)
  - Canton -- International Map of the World 1:1,000,000, 1942 (Item 6)
    Survey of India.
    Stamped "For official use only".
  - Hong Kong & Canton - China Scale 1:250,000, 1934 (Item 7)
    War Office.
    GSGS 3825.
- Maps of Chinese provinces and cities
  - Foreign Traveller's Guide Map of Shanghai, 1947 (Item 8)
    Oriental Publishing House Shanghai.
    Includes Shanghai Road Index on front and reverse.
  - [Merchants map of Shanghai], n.d. (Item 9)
    Advertisements along edges of map.
    Includes index to streets.
  - China, 1945 (Item 10)
    National Geographic.
    1:7,000,000.
  - Canton Harbour, 1939, Locations identified in English and Chinese. (Item 11)
  - Whampoa Anchorage, 1939, Locations identified in English and Chinese. (Item 12)
  - Shanghai Central District, n.d., Small map. (Item 13)
  - [193? Map of Nanning City Bombing], 1930 (Item 14)
    Depicts bombing.
    In Chinese.
  - [Guilin City], 1931 (Item 15)
    Index of merchants.
  - [Colored map of Guangxi Province], 1930 (Item 16)
    Inset maps of cities and rivers.
    Annotations on reverse in French and Chinese.
  - [Guangzhou Administrative Map], 1930? (Item 17)
    Shows districts and streets.
    In Chinese
    Annotations on reverse in German and Chinese.
- Various tourist maps
  - Map of Ireland. Scale: 12 miles to 1 inch. All Roads Classified..., 1949 (Item 18)
    Irish Tourist Association, Inc., Dublin.
    Ordnance Survey Office... Revised 1949.
  - Dolph's indexed street map of the Palm Beaches: Jupiter thru Lake Worth, Florida, n.d. (Item 19)
    Dolph Map Co., Inc.
    color map on front and black-and-white map on reverse.
  - Champion Map of Palm Beach County, Florida, n.d. (Item 20)
    Includes street index.
    Color map on front and reverse.
  - Esso -- New York City and Long Island map and visitor's guide, 1965 (Item 21)